<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>api on Michael Bumann</title>
    <link>https://michaelbumann.com/tags/api/</link>
    <description>Recent content in api on Michael Bumann</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 21:45:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://michaelbumann.com/tags/api/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitcoin lightning machine-to-machine API payments</title>
      <link>https://michaelbumann.com/posts/2018-11-22-bitcoin-lightning-machine-to-machine-api-payments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 21:45:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbumann.com/posts/2018-11-22-bitcoin-lightning-machine-to-machine-api-payments/</guid>
      <description>The Bitcoin lightning network is growing quickly. The lightning network is an exciting second layer protocol on top of the Bitcoin network that allows to send real near-instant payments and is perfectly suited for micro-/nano-transactions. The tools already work great and make it super easy for developers to integrate with the lightning network. I’ve lately experimented with it and built a demo to show machine-to-machine API payments. It allows the server to request a payment from the client; the client can automatically pay the invoice to access the resource from the server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experimenting with Bitcoin machine to machine payments</title>
      <link>https://michaelbumann.com/posts/2016-03-20-experimenting-with-bitcoin-machine-to-machine-payments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2016 07:16:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbumann.com/posts/2016-03-20-experimenting-with-bitcoin-machine-to-machine-payments/</guid>
      <description>We will see more and more machines directly and autonomously interacting with each other. Machines provide services to each other that are needed to fulfill their tasks.
Many tools that we are regularly using today are already mashups relying on different services and with the rise IoT&amp;nbsp;we will see only more devices consuming remote services and services directly from other devices.&amp;nbsp;
Providing services obviously also involves paying for these and this is where Bitcoin comes in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yo! - the most exciting application of 2014</title>
      <link>https://michaelbumann.com/posts/2014-12-10-yo-the-most-exciting-application-of-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 17:34:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://michaelbumann.com/posts/2014-12-10-yo-the-most-exciting-application-of-2014/</guid>
      <description>Yo! is probably one of the most exciting and strangest apps of 2014. What started on April Fools Day was suddenly a company valued at between $5 and $10 million in July and passed a million users just three months after its launch.
So what is Yo!?
The download page describes the app as the following:
 The simplest &amp;amp; most efficient communication tool in the world.
Yo is a single-tap zero character communication tool.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>